sure CHAPTER 19 IT HAS COME!" Of course Dr. Craven had been sent
for the morning after Colin had had his tantrum. He was always sent for at once
when such a thing occurred and he always found, when he arrived, a white shaken boy
lying on his bed, sulky and still so hysterical that he was ready to break
into fresh sobbing at the least word. In fact, Dr. Craven dreaded and
detested the difficulties of these visits.
On this occasion he was away from mleth Manor until
afternoon. "How is he?" he asked Mrs. Medlock rather irritably when he arrived. "He will
break a blood vessel in one of those fits someday The boy is half insane with hysteria and
self-indulgence." "Well, sir," answered Mrs.
Medlock, "you'll scarcely believe your eyes when you see him. That plain
sour-faced child that's almost as as bad as himself has just bewitched him. How
she's done it there's no telling. The Lord knows she's nothing to look at and
you scarcely ever hear her speak, but she did what none of us dare do. She just
flew at him like a little cat last night, and stamped her feet and ordered him to
stop screaming, and somehow she startled him so that he actually did stop, and
this afternoon— —well just come up and see, sir. It's past
crediting." The scene which Dr. Craven beheld when he entered his patient room
was indeed rather astonishing to him. As Mrs. Medlock opened the door he heard
laughing and chattering. Colin was on his sofa in his dressing gown and he was
sitting up quite straight looking at a picture in one of the garden books and
talking to the plain child who at that moment could scarcely be called plain at
all because her face was so glowing with enjoyment. "Those long buyers of blue ones—
—we'll have a lot of those," Colin was announcing. "They're called
delphiniums Dickon says their lar Spurs made big and grand," cried Mistress Mary.
"There are clumps there already." Then they saw Dr. Craven and
stopped. Mary became quite still and Colin looked
fretful. "I am sorry to hear you were ill last last night, my boy," Dr. Craven said a
trifle nervously. He was rather a nervous man. "I'm better now— —much better," Colin
answered rather like a Roger I'm going out in my chair in a day
or two if it is fine. I want some fresh
air." Dr. Craven sat down by him and felt his pulse and looked at him
curiously. "It must be a very fine day," he said, "and you must be very careful
careful not to tire yourself." "Fresh air won't tire me," said the young Roger As there had been
occasions when this same young gentleman had shrieked aloud with rage and had
insisted that fresh air would give him cold and kill him, it is not to be
wondered at that his doctor felt somewhat startled. "I thought you did not like
fresh air," he said. "I don't when I am by myself," replied the Raja but my cousin is
going out with me."
"And the nurse, of course?" suggested Dr.
Craven. "No, I will not have the nurse," so magnificently that Mary could not help
remembering how the young native Prince had looked with his diamonds and
emeralds and pearls stuck all over him and the great rubies on the small dark
hand he had waved to command his servants to approach with salams and receive his
orders. "My cousin knows how to take care of me. I am always better when she is
with me. She made me better last night. A very strong boy I know will push my
carriage." Dr. Craven felt rather alarmed.
If this tiresome hysterical boy should chance to get well he himself would lose
all chance of inheriting mlight but he was not an unscrupulous man, though he
was a weak one, and he did not intend to let him run into actual
danger. "He must be a strong boy and a steady boy," he said. "And I must know
something about him. Who is he? What is his name?" "It's Dickon," Mary spoke up
suddenly. She felt somehow that everybody who knew the more must know Dickon. And she was right,
too. She saw that in a moment Dr. Craven's serious face relaxed into a relieved
smile. "Oh, Dickon," he said. "If it is Dickon you will be safe enough. He's as strong
as a more pony as Dickon." "And he's trusty," said Mary. "He's the trustiest ly
Yorkshire." She had been talking Yorkshire to Colin and she forgot
herself. "Did Dickon teach you that?" asked Dr. Craven, laughing
outright. "I'm learning it as if it was French," said Mary rather coldly. "It's like
a native dialect in India. Very clever people try to learn them. I like it and
so does Colin." "Well, well," he said. "If it amuses you perhaps it won't do you any
harm. Did you take your bromide last night, Colin?" "No," Colin answered. "I wouldn't take
it at first and after Mary made me quiet she talked me to sleep— —in a low voice—
—about the spring creeping into a garden." "That sounds soothing," said Dr.
Craven, more perplexed than ever and glancing sideways at Mistress Mary
sitting on her stool and looking down silently at the carpet. "You are evidently better, but you
must remember—" "I don't want to remember," interrupted the Raja appearing again.
"When I lie by myself and remember I begin to have pains everywhere and I
think of things that make me begin to scream because I hate them so. If there
was a doctor anywhere who could make you forget you were ill instead of
remembering it I would have him brought here." And he waved a thin hand which
ought really to have been covered with royal signet rings made of
rubies. "It is because my cousin makes me forget that she makes me
better." Dr. Craven had never made such a short stay after a
"tantrum"; usually he was obliged to remain a very long time and do a great many
things. This afternoon he did not give any medicine or leave any new orders and
he was spared any disagreeable scenes. When he went downstairs he looked
very thoughtful and when he talked to Mrs. Medlock in the library she felt that
he was a much puzzled man. "Well, sir," she ventured, "could you have believed
it?" "It is certainly a new state of affairs," said the doctor. "And there's no
denying it is better than the old one." "I believe Susan Saab is right— —I do that,"
said Mrs. Medlock. "I stopped in her cottage on my way to thit yesterday and
had a bit of talk with her. And she says
to me, 'Well, Sarah Anne she may be a good
child and she may be a pretty one, but she's a child and children needs
children.' We went to school together, Susan sby and me." "She's the best sick
nurse I know," said Dr. Craven. "When I find her in a cottage I know the chances are
that I shall save my patient." Mrs. Medlock smiled. She was fond of Susan
sby She's got away with her, has Susan," she went on quite volubly. "I've been
thinking all morning of one thing she said yesterday. She says, 'Once when I was
giving the children a bit of a preach after after they'd been fighting I SS to them
all, "When I was at school my geography told as the world was shaped like a
orange and I found out before I was 10 that the whole orange doesn't belong to
nobody. No one owns more than his bit of a quarter and there's times it seems
like there's not an our quarters to go around But don't you— —none of you— —think
as you own the whole orange or you'll find out you're mistaken and you won't
find it out without hard knocks."
What children learns from children,' she says, 'is that there's no sense in
grabbing at the whole orange— —peel and all. If you do you'll likely not get even
the pips and them's too bitter to eat.'" "She's a shrewd woman," said Dr. Craven,
putting on his coat. "Well, she's got a way of saying things," ended Mrs. Medlock, much
pleased. "Sometimes I've said to her hey Susan, if you was a different woman and didn't
talk such broad Yorkshire I've seen the times when I should have said you was
clever.'" That night Colin slept without once awakening and when he opened his eyes in
the morning he lay still and smiled without knowing it— —smiled because he felt so curiously
comfortable. It was actually nice to be awake, and he turned over and stretched his limbs like
luxuriously. He felt as if tight strings which had held him had loosened themselves and let him
go. He did not know that Dr. Craven would have said that his nerves had relaxed and rested
themselves. Instead of lying and staring at the wall and wishing he had not
awakened, his mind was full of the plans he and Mary had made yesterday, of
pictures of the garden and of Dickon and his wild creatures. It was so nice to
have things to think about. And he had not been awake more than 10 minutes when
he heard feat running along the corridor and Mary was at the door. The next minute
she was in the room and had run across to his bed, bringing with her a waft of
fresh air full of the scent of the morning. "You've been out! You've been out!
There's that nice smell of leaves!" he cried. She had been running and her hair
was loose and blown and she was bright with the air and pink cheek though he
could not see it. "It's so beautiful!" she said, a little
breathless with her speed. "You never saw anything so beautiful! It has come I
thought it had come that other morning, but it was only coming. It is here now! It
has come, the Spring! Dickon says so!" "Has it?" cried Colin, and though he
really knew nothing about without it he felt his heartbeat He actually sat up in
bed. "Open the window!" he added, laughing half with joyful excitement and half at his own
fancy. "Perhaps we may hear golden trumpets!" And though he laughed, Mary was
at the window in a moment and in a moment more it was opened wide and
freshness and softness and scents and bird songs were pouring through.
"That's fresh air," she said. "Lie on your back and draw in long breaths of it.
That's what Dickon does when he's lying on the moall He says he feels it in his
veins and it makes him strong and he feels as if he could live forever and
ever. Breathe it and breathe it." She was only repeating what Dickon
had told her, but she caught Colin's fancy. "'Forever and ever'!
Does it make him feel like that?" he said, and he did as she told him, drawing in
long deep breaths over and over again until he felt that something quite new
and delightful was happening to him. Mary was at his bedside
again. "Things are crowding up out of the earth," she ran on in a hurry. "And there
are flowers uncurling and buds on everything and the green veil has
covered nearly all the gray and the birds are in such a hurry about their
nests for fear they may be too late that some of them are even fighting for
places in the secret garden. And the rose- bushes look as wick as wick can be, and
there are Prim roses in the lanes and woods, and the seeds we planted are up,
and Dickon has brought the fox and the crow and the squirrels and a newborn
lamb." And then she paused for breath. The newborn lamb lamb Dickon had
found 3 days before lying by its dead mother among the gor bushes on the mo It
was not the first motherless lamb he had found and he knew what to do with it. He
had taken it to the cottage wrapped in his jacket and he had let it lie near
the fire and had fed it with warm milk.
It was a soft thing with a darling silly baby face and legs rather long for its
body. Dickon had carried it over the mo in his arms and its feeding bottle was
in his pocket with a squirrel, and when Mary had sat under a tree with its limp
warmness huddled on her lap she had felt as if she were too full of strange joy
to speak. A lamb— —a lamb! A living lamb who lay on your lap like a
baby! She was describing it with great joy and Colin was listening and drawing
in long breath of air when the nurse entered. She started a little at the
sight of the open window. She had sat stifling in the room many a warm day
because her patient was sure that open windows gave people
cold. "Are you sure you are not chilly, Master Colin?" she inquired. "No," was the answer. "I am
breathing long breaths of fresh air. It makes you strong. I going to get up to
the sofa for breakfast and my cousin will have breakfast with
me." The nurse went away, concealing a smile, to give the order for two
breakfasts. She found the servants' hall a more amusing place than the invalid's
chamber and just now everybody wanted to hear the news from upstairs There was a great deal of
joking about the unpopular young recluse who, as the cook said, "had found his
master, and good friend for him." The servants' hall had been very tired of the
tantrums, and the butler, who was a man with a family, had more than once
expressed his opinion that the invalid would be all the better "for a good
hiding." When Colin was on his sofa and the breakfast for two was put upon the
table he made an announcement to the nurse in his most Raja like
manner. "A boy, and a fox, and a crow, and two squirrels, and a newborn lamb, are
coming to see me this morning. I want them brought upstairs as soon as they
come," he said. "You are not to begin playing with the animals in the servants'
hall and keep them there. I want them here." The nurse gave a slight gasp and
tried to conceal it with a cough. "Yes, sir," she answered. "I'll tell you what you can
do," added Colin, waving his hand. "You can tell Martha to bring them here. The boy
is Martha's brother. His name is Dickon and he is an animal
charmer." "I hope the animals won't bite, Master Colin," said the
nurse. "I told you he was a charmer," said Colin austerely. "Charmers' animals never
bite." "There are snake Charmers in India," said Mary; "and they can put their snakes'
heads in their mouths." "Goodness shuted the nurse.
They ate their breakfast with the morning air pouring in upon them Collins
breakfast was a very good one am Mary watched him with serious
interest. "You will begin to get fatter just as I did," she said. "I never wanted my
breakfast when I was in India and now I always want it." "I wanted mine this morning," said
Colin. "Perhaps it was the fresh air. When do you think Dickon will come?"
He was not long in coming. In about 10 minutes Mary held up her hand. "Listen!" she
said. "Did you hear a COR Colin listened and heard it, the oddest sound in the
world to hear inside a house, a horse cor cor Yes," he
answered. "That's Soot," said Mary. "Listen again! Do you hear a bleet a tiny one?" "Oh,
yes!" cried Colin, quite flushing. "That's the newborn lamb," said Mary. "He's
coming dickens's morand boots were thick and clumsy and though he tried to walk
quietly they made a clumping sound as he walked through the long
corridors. Mary and Colin heard him marching— —marching, until he passed
through the tapestry door onto the soft carpet of Colin's own
passage. "If you please, sir," announced Martha, opening the door, "if you please,
sir, here's Dickon and his creatures." "DICKON CAME IN SMILING HIS
NICEST WIDE SMILE The newborn lamb was in his arms and the little red fox
trotted by his side. Nut sat on his left shoulder and so on his right and Shell's
head and paws peeped out of his coat pocket. Colin slowly sat up and stared
and stared— —as he had stared when he first saw Mary; but this was a stare of
wonder and delight. The truth was that in spite of
all he had heard he had not in the least understood what this boy would be like
and that his fox and his crow and his squirrels and his lamb were so near to
him and his friendliness that they seemed almost to be part of himself.
Colin had never talked to a boy in his life and he was so overwhelmed by his
own pleasure and curiosity that he did not even think of speaking. But Dickon did not feel the
least shy or awkward. He had not felt embarrassed because the crow had not
known his language and had only stared and had not spoken to him the first time they
met. Creatures were always like that until they found out about
you. He walked over to Colin's sofa and put the newborn lamb quietly on his lap,
and immediately the little creature turned to the warm velvet dressing gown
and began to nuzzle and nuzzle into its folds and butt its tight curled head
with soft impatience against his side. Of course no boy could have helped speaking
then. "What is it doing?" cried Colin. "What does it want?" "It wants its mother," said Dickon,
smiling more and more. "I brought it to thee a bit hungry because I know that'd
like to see it feed." He knelt down by the sofa and took a feeding bottle from his
pocket. "Come on, little he said, turning the small woolly white head with a gentle brown
hand. "This is what that's after they'll get more out of this than thou will out
of silk velvet coats then now," and he pushed the rubber tip of the bottle into the nuzzling
mouth and the lamb began to suck it with ravenous
ecstasy. After that there was no wondering what to say. By the time the lamb fell asleep
questions poured forth and Dickon answered them all. He told them how he had found the
lamb just as the sun was rising three mornings ago. He had been standing on the
Moore listening to a Skylock and watching him swing higher and higher
into the sky until he was only a speck in the heights of blue.
"I'd almost lost him but for his song and I was wondering how a chap could hear it
when it seemed as if he'd get out of the
world in a minute and just then I heard something else far off among the gor
bushes. It was a weak bleeting and I knowed it was a new lamb as was hungry
and I knowed it wouldn't be hungry if it hadn't lost its mother somehow, so I set off
searching I did have a look for it. I went in and out among the G horse bushes
and round and round and I always seemed to take the wrong turn in But at last I
seed a bit of wi by a rock on top of the
Moore and I climbed up and found the little and half dead with cold and
Clemen While he talked suot flew solemnly in and out of the open window
and CED remarks about the scenery while Nut and Shell made excursions into the
big trees outside and ran up and down trunks and explored branches.
Captain curled up near Dickon, who sat on the Hearth rug from
preference. They looked at the pictures in the gardening books and Dickon knew
all the flowers by their country names and knew exactly which ones were already
growing in the secret garden. "I couldn't say that their name," he
said, pointing to one under which was written aquilia but us calls that a Coline and
that their one it's a snap dragon and they both grow wild in hedges, but these
is garden ones and they're bigger and grander. There's some big clumps of
Coline in the garden. They'll look like a bed of blue and white butterflies
fluttering when they're out." "I'm going to see them," cried Colin. "I am going to see
them I that that said Mary quite seriously and that man not lose no time about it